Register of the Albert C. Wedemeyer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SECOND UNITED STATES ARMY (1946 SEPTEMBER-1947 OCTOBER) FILE, 1935-1950 (Boxes 92-97)
  - Correspondence
    - Rhee, Syngman, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 75)
    - Robertson, Walter S., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 76)
    - Roosevelt, Quentin, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 77)
    - Royall, Kenneth C., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 78)
    - Schoyer, B. Preston, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 79)
    - Sikorsky, Igor I., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 80)
    - Smith, Bruce M., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 81)
    - Smith, Linton B., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 82)
    - Smyth, Robert L., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 83)
    - Soong, T. V., 1946-1947 (Box-folder 94: 1)
    - Spaatz, Carl, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 2)
    - Spiker, C. J., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 3)
    - Stamps, D. F., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 4)
    - Stettinius, Edward, Jr., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 5)
    - Stewart, G. C., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 6)
    - Stuart, J. Leighton, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 7)
    - Sun, Soong Ching Ling (Madame Sun Yat-sen), 1947 (Box-folder 94: 8)
    - Talbot, Phillips, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 9)
    - Ting, K., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 10)
    - Trippe, J. T., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 11)
    - Tseng, Hsi-kuei, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 12)
    - Tu, Chien-shih, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 13)
    - Turner, William, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 14)
    - Tweedy, Gordon B., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 15)
    - United Service to China (Mrs. John G. Coolidge), 1947 (Box-folder 94: 16)
    - Utley, Freda, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 17)
    - Van Brunt, Winslow, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 18)
    - Vance, J. R., 1946 (Box-folder 94: 19)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 20)
    - Wagoner, John A., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 21)
    - Wang, Shih-chieh, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 22)
    - Wang, Shou Chin, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 23)
    - Ward, Angus, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 24)
    - Warner, Gerald, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 25)
    - Weckerling, John, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 26)
    - Wedemeyer, Mrs. A. A., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 27)
    - Wedemeyer, A. D., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 28)
    - Wei, Tao-ming, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 29)
    - William, Maurice, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 30)
    - Willis, Priscilla, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 31)
    - Willoughby, Charles A., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 32)
    - Woolnough, James, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 33)
    - Wu, Chang Ying, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 34)
    - Wu, K. C. and Edith, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 35)
    - Yancey, William, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 36)
    - Yao, Hsin-nung, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 37)
    - Yeaton, Ivan, 1946 (Box-folder 94: 38)
    - Young China Party (Tsien Chung Chou), 1947 (Box-folder 94: 39)
    - Yu, P. C., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 40)
      Includes a speech by Yu.
    - Yu, Ta-wei, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 41)
    - Yui, O. K., 1947 (Box-folder 94: 42)
  - Subject file
    - China
      Contains material relating to the Wedemeyer Mission to China in 1947.
      - General. Index, maps, and printed article, 1937-1947 (Box-folder 94: 43)
      - Politics and government
        - General (Box-folder 94: 44)
          Clippings, memoranda, notes, speeches by Chiang Kai-shek, typescript copies of reports, including "A General Statement Concerning Policies of the Chinese Government and their Implementation," Percy G. Black,"Comments on China," Joseph E. Jacobs, "Some Observations on the Situation in China," Lewis L. Leavell, "Cliques Within the Kuomintang and an Estimation Regarding its Capacity to Retain Governmental Control of China," Charles C. Stelle, "Contemporary China," and David N. Rowe, "Chinese Revolution" (with discussion transcript).
        - Communists. Clippings, memoranda, notes, and typescript reports, including answers to questions compiled by Chen Chih-mai at Wedemeyer's request, and Wang Shih-chieh, "Negotiation with the Chinese Communists,", 1945-1947 (Box-folder 94: 45)
    - Communism. Typescript copy of a legal brief, and mimeographed copy of a War Department report, "Study Showing the Relationship Between Jews and Communism,", 1946-1947 (Box-folder 94: 46)
    - Europe. Typescript reports by Wedemeyer, "Observations in Europe," and Kurt Hesse, "Will There Be a War?," memoranda, and mimeographed notes for a seminar series entitled "Britain's Power Position,", 1946-1947 (Box-folder 94: 47)
    - Middle East. Short typescript and lecture transcript, 1947 (Box-folder 94: 48)
    - Nuclear weapons. Typescript report, "The Effects of the Atomic Bomb on National Security,", 1947 (Box-folder 94: 49)
    - Soviet Union, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 94: 50)
      Transcription of a Canadian government report relating to Soviet espionage activity in that country, American-Russian Chamber of Commerce bulletin, "The Five-Year-Plan Program for the Restoration and Development of the Economy of U.S.S.R. for the Years 1946-1950," and typescript War Department reports relating to the Soviet presence in the Far East.
    - Steel. Mimeograph War Department report, "Location and Accessibility to United States of Steel Hardening Elements,", 1946 (Box-folder 94: 51)
    - United States-Foreign relations
      - General. Printed articles, flyer, and mimeographed lectures by George F. Kennan, "Comments on the National Security Problem," and G. A. Lincoln, "Postwar Planning,", 1946-1947 (Box-folder 95: 1)
      - China
        - General, 1935-1947 (Box-folder 95: 2-3)
          Reports, statements by Walter H. Judd and Robert P. Patterson, memoranda, notes, pamphlets, treaty texts, clippings, miscellany, proposals, letters, and typescript copies of Percy G. Black, "Comments on China," Owen Lattimore, "Far East in World Politics," and War Department reports, "American Aid for China," and "The Possibility of a Marshall Plan for the Far East."
        - Wedemeyer Mission
          - General. Notes, memoranda, printed articles by Liu Hua-jui, letters, speech by C. A. Trexel, clipping, press release, miscellany, and a mimeographed War Department report, "A Comparison of the Effectiveness of the Chinese Communist Forces and the Chinese National Government Forces,", 1947 (Box-folder 95: 4)
          - Appointment logs and schedules, 1947 (Box-folder 95: 5)
          - Directives, 1947 (Box-folder 95: 6)
          - Intelligence file. Messages, memoranda, and reports, 1947 (Box-folder 95: 7)
            Primarily relating to the Chinese communists and Soviet activity in China.
          - Messages and memoranda, 1947 July - September
            - General. Communications between Wedemeyer and George Marshall (Box-folder 95: 8)
            - Incoming
              - General (Box-folder 96: 1)
              - War Department ("Opal") (Box-folder 96: 2)
            - Outgoing
              - General (Box-folder 96: 3)
              - War Department ("Jade") (Box-folder 96: 4)
          - Meeting minutes, 1947 July - August (Box-folder 96: 5)
          - Personnel file. Memoranda, messages, and orders, 1947 July - September (Box-folder 96: 6)
          - Press and public relations file. Clippings, press releases, memoranda, messages, letters, and notes, 1947 July - October (Box-folder 97: 1-2)
          - Reports. Typescript copy of United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, China Office, "Information on Agricultural Rehabilitation Program," and A. C. Wedemeyer, "Report to the President," with distribution memorandum and letter, 1947 August - October (Box-folder 97: 3)
          - Trip file. Memoranda and messages, 1947 July - September (Box-folder 97: 4)
          - Subject file. Korea
            - General. Memoranda, reports, letter, miscellany, and typescript copy of Joseph E. Jacobs, "Political Observations on Korea,", 1947 July - September (Box-folder 97: 5)
            - Chronological file. Notes, memoranda, letters, and messages, 1947 July - September (Box-folder 97: 6-7)
    - United States-Military. Memorandum, bibliography, speech by J. E. Schaefer, and mimeographed report by George (?) Lincoln, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 97: 8)
- PLANS AND OPERATIONS DIVISION, GENERAL STAFF, UNITED STATES ARMY (1947 OCTOBER-1948 NOVEMBER) FILE, 1942-1948 (Boxes 98-99)
  Correspondence, memoranda, speeches, press releases, reports, lists, notes, printed material, and miscellany, arranged by form, thereunder by subject.
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 1)
    - Almond, Edward M., 1947 (Box-folder 98: 2)
    - Aurand, Henry S., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 3)
      Includes comments by Paul Caraway on a report by Aurand.
    - Barr, David, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 4)
    - Berendsen, F. J., 1947 (Box-folder 98: 5)
    - Bolton, Frances P., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 6)
    - Bridges, Styles, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 7)
    - Brink, Francis, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 8)
    - Bush, Vannevar, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 9)
    - Byrd, Richard E., undated (Box-folder 98: 10)
    - Calder, Bland, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 11)
    - Canham, Erwin D., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 12)
    - Caraway, Paul, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 13)
    - Carton de Wiart, Adrian, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 14)
    - Chang, Carsun, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 15)
    - Chen, Chih-mai, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 16)
    - Chiang, Kai-shek, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 17)
    - Chinese Farmers' Party (Tung Shih-Tsin), 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 18)
    - Clay, Lucius, 1947 (Box-folder 98: 19)
    - Cooke, Charles M., Jr., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 20)
    - Creel, George, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 21)
      Includes typescript copy of a book review of Creel's memoirs.
    - Donovan, William, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 22)
    - Dzung, Kenyon, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 23)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 24)
    - Ford, John, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 25)
    - Forrestal, James, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 26)
    - Gerow, L. T., 1947 (Box-folder 98: 27)
    - Goddard, R. Victor, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 28)
    - Gould, Randall, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 29)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 30)
    - Hays, George P., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 31)
    - Hickerson, John, undated (Box-folder 98: 32)
    - Hillenkoetter, R. H., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 33)
    - Ho, Ying-Chin, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 34)
      Includes a copy of a speech by Ho.
    - Hodge, John R., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 35)
    - Hoge, W. M., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 36)
    - Howard, Roy, letter to Bernard Baruch, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 37)
    - Huebner, C. R., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 38)
    - Hull, J. E., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 39)
    - Hull, Richard A., 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 40)
    - Hurley, Patrick, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 41)
    - Judd, Walter, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 42)
      Includes a press release issued by Patrick Hurley.
    - Keyes, Geoffrey, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 43)
    - Kilbourne, C. E., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 44)
    - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 45)
    - Koo, V. K. Wellington, 1947 (Box-folder 98: 46)
    - Krueger, Walter, 1947 (Box-folder 98: 47)
    - Kung, H. H., 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 48)
    - Landon, Alf M., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 49)
    - Leahy, William D., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 50)
    - Levine, Isaac Don, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 51)
    - Lincoln, George A., 1947 (Box-folder 98: 52)
    - Lindbergh, Charles, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 53)
    - Linebarger, Paul M. A., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 54)
    - Littell, Robert, 1947 (Box-folder 98: 55)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1947 (Box-folder 98: 56)
    - Lovett, Robert A., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 57)
    - MacArthur, Douglas and Jean, 1947 (Box-folder 98: 58)
    - McBride, Horace L., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 59)
    - McNamee, Roland, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 60)
    - Marshall, George C., 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 61)
    - Montgomery, Bernard L., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 62)
    - Mountbatten, Louis, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 63)
    - Mueller, Paul J., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 64)
    - Norstad, Lauris, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 65)
    - Omurtak, Salih, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 66)
    - Overseas Writers, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 67)
    - Pai, Chung-hsi, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 68)
    - Rickenbacker, Edward M., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 69)
    - Ridgway, Matthew B., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 70)
    - Smith, Walter Bedell, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 71)
    - Smith, Truman, 1947 (Box-folder 98: 72)
    - Sokolsky, George, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 73)
    - Speth, Hans, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 74)
    - Stimson, Henry L., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 75)
    - Stuart, Leighton, 1948 (Box-folder 98: 76)
    - Taylor, Maxwell D., 1948 (Box-folder 98: 77)
    - Walsh, Robert L., 1947-1948 (Box-folder 98: 78)
  - Memoranda, 1948 January - November (Box-folder 98: 79)
  - Schedules, 1947 November 13 - December 7 (Box-folder 98: 80)
  - Subject file
    - East Asia. Pamphlet, press release, and newsletter, 1948 (Box-folder 99: 1)
    - European Recovery Program (Marshall Plan). Mimeograph report, 1947 (Box-folder 99: 2)
    - Finland. Memoranda, 1948 (Box-folder 99: 3)
    - Germany. Memorandum relating to the Nuremberg trials, two typescript book reviews by Stanley Embick, and a letter to Michael Faulhaber, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 99: 4)
    - Intelligence. Memoranda, letter by F. S. Doll, lists, and map, 1948 (Box-folder 99: 5)
    - Korea. Resolution, printed excerpts, and letters by B. C. Limb and Cornelius Osgood, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 99: 6)
    - Middle East. Typescript report, speech by Lawrence H. Smith, printed excerpts, and letters by Percy G. Black and others, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 99: 7)
    - Soviet Union. Mimeograph copies of Joseph K. Dickey, "The U.S.S.R.," printed excerpt, and letter by Boris A. Bakhmeteff, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 99: 8)
    - United States-Foreign relations
      - General. Mimeograph and typescript reports, letters, statement by James Forrestal, and a memorandum of conversation with Averell Harriman, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 99: 9-10)
      - China, 1942-1948 (Box-folder 99: 11)
        Typescript copy of an interview with Charles Cooke, memoranda, clippings, statistical reports, mimeograph congressional report, speeches, statements by Douglas MacArthur and Walter Robertson, printed copy of P. C. Yu, "A Study of the Present Military Situation in China," and correspondence with Lee Hagood, Tzon Fah Hwang, Ernest Moy, Kenneth C. Royall, C. H. Wong and others.
    - United States-Military. Memorandum, speech by Alf Landon, and list relating to African-American personnel, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 99: 12)
    - World War II. Strategic planning notes, undated (Box-folder 99: 13)
- OFFICE OF THE CHIEF OF STAFF, UNITED STATES ARMY (1948 NOVEMBER-1949 SEPTEMBER) FILE, 1948-1949 (Boxes 100-101)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, speeches, statistics, notes, printed material, and miscellany, arranged by form, thereunder by subject.
  - General. List, orders, and a personnel report, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 2)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 3)
    - Barr, David, 1948 (Box-folder 100: 4)
    - Bellah, James W., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 5)
    - Bridges, Styles, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 6)
    - Brink, Francis, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 7)
    - Calder, Bland, 1948 (Box-folder 100: 8)
    - Chen, Chih-mai, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 9)
      Includes a book review by Chen.
    - Chen, Li-fu, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 10)
    - Chen, Cheng, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 11)
    - Chennault, Claire L., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 12)
      Includes letters by Hung Chung Cheh.
    - Chiang, Kai-shek and Mei-ling Soong Chiang, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 13)
      Includes a letter by Peter Pee.
    - Chiang, Yun-tien, 1948 (Box-folder 100: 14)
    - Chough, Pyung Ok, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 15)
    - Chun, Arthur, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 16)
    - Clark, Ronald, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 17)
    - Connor, Voris H., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 18)
      Includes writing by Connor.
    - Conolly, R. L., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 19)
    - Coulter, John B., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 20)
    - Creel, George, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 21)
    - Culbertson, Ely, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 22)
    - Davenport, Harold A., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 23)
    - Davies, John, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 24)
    - Dewey, Bradley, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 25)
    - Donovan, William J., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 26)
    - Draper, William H., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 27)
    - Dzung, K. V., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 28)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 29)
    - Fasano, Rodolfo, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 30)
    - Ford, John, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 31)
    - Forrestal, James, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 32)
    - Garside, B. A., 1948 (Box-folder 100: 33)
    - Gerow, L. T., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 34)
    - Goddard, Victor, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 35)
    - Goodenough, Michael, 1948 (Box-folder 100: 36)
    - Grady, Henry F., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 37)
    - Gray, Gordon, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 38)
    - Greenwood, Joseph R., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 39)
    - Greunther, Alfred M., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 40)
    - Handy, Thomas T., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 41)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 42)
    - Henderson, Loy, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 43)
    - Hill, H. W., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 44)
    - Ho, Ying-chin, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 45)
    - Hodges, Courtney, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 46)
    - Huebner, C. R., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 47)
    - Hull, J. E., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 48)
    - Hurley, Patrick, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 49)
    - Irish, C. G., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 50)
    - Jacobs, Joseph E., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 51)
    - Jessup, Philip C., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 52)
    - Jones, A. M., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 53)
    - Kleffens, E. N. van, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 54)
    - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 55)
    - Krock, Arthur, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 56)
    - Kung, H. H., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 57)
    - Lattre de Tassigny, Jean de, 1948 (Box-folder 100: 58)
    - Li, Tsung-jen, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 59)
    - Limon, Gilberto R., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 60)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 61)
    - Lovink, A. H. J., 1948 (Box-folder 100: 62)
    - Luce, Henry R., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 63)
    - MacArthur, Douglas, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 64)
    - Maddocks, Ray T., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 65)
    - Mansfield, Walter R., 1948 (Box-folder 100: 66)
    - Marshall, George C., 1948 (Box-folder 100: 67)
    - Mathews, William R., 1949 (Box-folder 100: 68)
    - Montgomery, Bernard L., 1948 (Box-folder 100: 69)
    - Moorad, George, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 70)
    - Mountbatten, Louis, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 100: 71)
    - Neprud, Carl, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 72)
    - Niblo, Urban, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 73)
    - Nickerson, Hoffman, 1949 (Box-folder 100: 74)
    - Norstad, Lauris, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 1)
    - Ouang, Max and Eppy, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 2)
    - Pechkoff, Z., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 3)
    - Pee, Peter T. K., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 4)
    - Pegler, Westbrook, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 5)
    - Pollard, George M., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 6)
    - Pridi Debyabongs, Prince, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 7)
    - Revers, General, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 101: 8)
    - Ridgway, Matthew, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 9)
    - Robertson, H. C. H., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 10)
    - Rush, George L., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 11)
    - Slim, William J., 1948 (Box-folder 101: 12)
    - Smith, Truman, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 13)
    - Sokolsky, George, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 14)
    - Stratemeyer, George E., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 15)
      Includes a press release.
    - Sun, Li-Jen, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 16)
    - Taylor, B. F., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 17)
    - Taylor, Henry, 1948 (Box-folder 101: 18)
    - Tunner, William H., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 19)
    - Walker, Walton, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 20)
    - Walsh, Edmund A., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 101: 21)
    - Wang, Chi-yuan, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 22)
    - Watson, Mark, 1948 (Box-folder 101: 23)
    - Wheeler, R. A., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 24)
    - Whitehead, Ennis C., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 25)
    - Willoughby, Charles A., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 26)
    - Wu, K. C., 1949 (Box-folder 101: 27)
  - Memoranda, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 101: 28)
  - Subject file
    - Burma. Printed excerpts of speeches by Thakin Nu, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 29)
    - China, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 101: 30-31)
      Clippings, memoranda, statistics, notes, statements by Dean Acheson, Patrick Hurley, and Walter Judd, reports, typescript copies of "U.S. Policy in China," "Report by the Joint Strategic Survey Committee to the Joint Chiefs of Staff on the China White Paper," Lee Hagood, "Chinese Communists and American Security," mimeograph copies of "Personal Comments and Observations of Roger D. Lapham on 'The China Problem,'" "United States Government Economic, Financial, and Military Aid to China Since 1937," William R. Johnson, "Falsehoods and Some Truths about China and America's China Policy," and letters by Harwood C. Bowman, Chiang Yun-tien, Robert T. Elson, Roger D. Lapham, Daniel Longwell, Walter Robertson and others.
    - Europe. Translated article, "The Defense of Western Europe,", 1949 (Box-folder 101: 32)
    - Germany. Memoranda and letter by Joan S. Crane, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 33)
    - Great Britain. Pamphlet, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 34)
    - Indonesia. United Nations report, clipping, and correspondence with William S. B. Lacy, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 35)
    - Italy. Memorandum, draft outline, and letter by Wedemeyer to Mark Clark, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 36)
    - Japan. Letters by Joseph M. Dodge, Ward Maris, Tomozo Ogawa and another, and memoranda, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 37)
    - Korea. Memorandum of conversation with Syngman Rhee, Kenneth Royall, and another, resolution, and correspondence with Chough Pyung Ok and William L. Roberts, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 101: 38)
    - Soviet Union. Memoranda, statements by Arthur Bliss Lane and Grigori A. Tokaev, and correspondence with Alexander Jannes and others, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 101: 39)
    - Spain. Letter by William Perry George, 1948 (Box-folder 101: 40)
    - United States-Military Assistance Program. Memorandum, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 41)
    - Venezuela. Memorandum, 1949 (Box-folder 101: 42)
- SIXTH UNITED STATES ARMY (1949 SEPTEMBER-1951 JULY) FILE, 1949-1951 (Boxes 102-104)
  Correspondence, speeches, memoranda, reports, notes, newsletters, resolutions, lists, and miscellany, arranged by form, thereunder by subject.
  - Correspondence
    - American War Correspondents Association, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 1)
    - Baldwin, Hanson W., 1950 (Box-folder 102: 2)
    - Barrett, David, 1951 (Box-folder 102: 3)
    - Baruch, Bernard, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 4)
    - Bendetsen, Karl R., 1951 (Box-folder 102: 5)
    - Berendsen, Friedrich J., 1950 (Box-folder 102: 6)
    - Boker, Alexander, 1951 (Box-folder 102: 7)
    - Bradley, Omar, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 8)
    - Brink, Francis G., 1950 (Box-folder 102: 9)
    - Brooks, Deton J., Jr., 1951 (Box-folder 102: 10)
    - Bull, H. R., 1950 (Box-folder 102: 11)
    - Carton de Wiart, Adrian, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 12)
    - Chang, Fa-Kwei, 1951 (Box-folder 102: 13)
    - Chang, T. K., 1950 (Box-folder 102: 14)
    - Chen, Chih-mai, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 15)
    - Chiang, Kai-shek and Mei-ling Soong Chiang, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 102: 16)
    - Chieh, Hwang, 1949 (Box-folder 102: 17)
    - Chow, Chih-Jou, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 102: 18)
    - Clubb, Edmund, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 19)
    - Collins, J. Lawton, 1951 (Box-folder 102: 20)
    - Crane, Durries, 1951 (Box-folder 102: 21)
    - Creel, George, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 22)
    - Culbertson, Ely, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 23)
    - D'Alesandro, Thomas, Jr., 1950 (Box-folder 102: 24)
    - Dewey, Bradley, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 25)
    - Dodge, Joseph, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 102: 26)
    - Douglas, L. W., 1950 (Box-folder 102: 27)
    - Downey, S. W., 1949 (Box-folder 102: 28)
    - Duff, James H., 1950 (Box-folder 102: 29)
    - Dupuy, R. Ernest, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 30)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1949-1951 (Box-folder 102: 31)
    - Ferrin, C. S., 1950 (Box-folder 102: 32)
    - Ford, John, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 33)
    - Gould, Randall, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 102: 34)
    - Gruenther, A. M., 1949 (Box-folder 102: 35)